<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on xhocquet.info</title>
    <link>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on xhocquet.info</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 16:32:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://xhocquet.info/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buffalo Sauce</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/buffalo-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 16:32:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/buffalo-sauce/</guid>
      <description> Ingredients 1 cup melted butter 2/3 cup Frank&#39;s RedHot 1 splash vinegar Directions Combine ingredients in a saucepan over low heat for 5 - 10 minutes. Serve </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classic Baguettes</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/classic-baguettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 16:32:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/classic-baguettes/</guid>
      <description>source Ingredients Starter (Poolish) 113 grams cool water 1/16 teaspoon acive dry yeast or instant yeast 120 grams unbleached all-purpose flour Dough 1 1/2 teaspoon active dry yeast or instant yeast 255 grams lukewarm water 418 grams unbleached all-purpose flour 2 teaspoons salt Summary Make starter and let rest overnight Make dough and let rest 45 + 45 minutes Split dough and let rest 15 minutes - 1 hour Shape loaves, let rest 45 minutes - 1 hour Bake ~30 minutes Directions Starter (Poolish) Mix ingredients together to make a soft dough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Korean Beef Lettuce Wraps</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/korean-lettuce-wraps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 10:21:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/korean-lettuce-wraps/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 head lettuce with large leaves 1 lb. ground beef ½ cup brown sugar ¼ cup soy sauce/tamari 1 tablespoon sesame oil; divided in half 3 cloves garlic; minced/grated ¼ teaspoon ground ginger 1 bunch green onions; divided between white and green parts 3 tablespoon rice wine vinegar ⅛ teaspoon red pepper flakes (optional and to taste) Additional Garnish Spicy mayonaise Sesame seeds Recipe Combine brown sugar, soy sauce/tamari, half the sesame oil, garlic, ginger, rice wine vinegar, and (optional) red pepper flakes; set aside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traditional Mayonnaise</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/mayonnaise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 20:21:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/mayonnaise/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 egg yolk 1 tablespoon good, strong mustard 1 splash vinegar 100 ml oil (olive or avocado for example) salt pepper Recipe Get all your ingredients to room temperature (🚨) Mix together the egg yolk, mustard, vinegar, salt, and pepper Make an emulsion by vigorously whisking the oil into the mixture in small amounts. Optionally add some lemon or herbs to flavor </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick-n-Dirty Crusty Bread</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/quick-n-dirty-crusty-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 20:21:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/recipes/quick-n-dirty-crusty-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients&#xA;3 cups lukewarm water 2 lbs. unbleached all-purpose flour 1 tablespoon salt 1 ½ tablespoons instant or active dry yeast Directions&#xA;Combine all of the ingredients in a large mixing bowl Mix by hand to make a very sticky, rough dough. Cover the bowl, and let the dough rise at room temperature for 2 hours. (optional in case of rush) Refrigerate for 2 hours to 7 days. 2 hours will be pretty bland.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
