<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tech on xhocquet.info</title>
    <link>http://xhocquet.info/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tech on xhocquet.info</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:40:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://xhocquet.info/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Unfortunate Dichotomy of Security and Accessibility</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/security-and-accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:40:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/security-and-accessibility/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been paying attention to the recent WhatsApp fiasco and noticed a disappointing pattern from potential users learning about alternative services.
WhatsApp recently updated their terms of service which sparked a vigorous discussion online about data collection and services being bought up by other companies. Whether or not the change is meaningful (given that they were already deeply embedded with Facebook) is up for debate, but it did trigger a lot of questions online about alternatives and what options users had to fight back against data collection in their everyday lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bias Balancer</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/bias-balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:05:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/bias-balancer/</guid>
      <description>The past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a tiny little project that&amp;rsquo;s been on my mind.
So I want to introduce: Bias Balancer!
We all know bias exists, but we tend to passively acknowledge it instead of actively fighting back. Like most problems, the first step is education and awareness. I wanted a way to measure bias in my browsing habits so that I could take steps to remedy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Tracking (update!)</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/music-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 08:47:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/music-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is a brief update to my previous post.
Music Tracking I wanted to write this post primarily to brag + advertise my recent improvements in music library management thanks to some fantastic software I recently discovered: beets.
Beets is a lot of things, and if you sit on their current homepage long enough their taglines will boast their many, many features. At a high level though, beets is a tool to organize your music library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Tracking</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/media-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 20:04:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/media-tracking/</guid>
      <description>I love tracking things. It feeds my need to always be up-to-date on my progress. I feel that by knowing my status at all times, I can optimize my decisions at any moment to increase my productivity. Some may call that over-optimizing, but I believe it&amp;rsquo;s part of who I am and lets me perform at a high level while maintaining free time.
This happens on a bunch of levels, for example: In the morning, I&amp;rsquo;m tracking the train moving through the city until it reaches my stop to optimize when I should go to bed and wake up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ode to Gmail&#39;s Attachment Reminder</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/gmail-attachment-reminder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 15:26:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/gmail-attachment-reminder/</guid>
      <description>Rarely do features surprise me these days. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen every iteration of create, read, update, destroy you could think of in dozens of technologies of varying complexities and interoperability. Sometimes you have to wait for things, sometimes you need to display a lot of information.
Because of this, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worthy to whip out a small post congratulating and celebrating the little things that keep our lives in order. This feature is as dumb as can be: When you type certain phrases that imply an attachment should be present, Gmail warns you if there&amp;rsquo;s no attachment before sending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting my Electronic Life: Part 2</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/security-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 20:43:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/security-part-2/</guid>
      <description>After some common-sense practices to use, I wanted to switch over to privacy and data online and off. Your privacy is literally under attack every day from countless sources, usually trying to pry out as much data from your activity as they can without breaking the law. I used to not care. I felt that since I had nothing to hide, it didn’t bother me that some companies could use my data points to make new things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting my Electronic Life: Part 1</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/security-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:44:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/security-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Technology scares me. I consider myself lucky in that I can navigate it and make educated decisions, but at the same time I realize that I rely on hundreds of technologies every day and I don&amp;rsquo;t even know how they work!
The most frightening thing is how fast it’s all happening. I thought I would be up-to-date for much longer than my parents were, or even my peers are today. It turns out another internet-addicted generation is already steadily replacing my idea of normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Javascript Hack-o-thon Project 1</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/meteor-angular-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 21:20:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/meteor-angular-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Meteor Exploration (and friend, Angular) I decided to look into Meteor because of it&amp;rsquo;s general popularity in enterprise. I was curious what made it attractive versus a typical app with Angular or React backed by some data store.
Meteor offers generous documentation and tutorials, one of which I decided to follow. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too interested in diving into mobile at this time, so I stuck with their simple to-do app. I promised myself I would add some kind of extra feature after the tutorial ended to prove I understood a basic amount of the framework</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Code Style for Developer Happiness</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/optimizing-code-style-for-dev-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 11:52:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/optimizing-code-style-for-dev-happiness/</guid>
      <description>While I started my programming career closer to the hardware with C, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to be comfortable as web dev using Ruby and Javascript as my main languages. Ruby will be my focus in this post, but believe the two languages share more similarities than most realize.
These days, it feels like more and more time passes between each time I write code. Everyone on my career path goes through it, but as you graduate past a junior role you start to offer more and more of your time to others instead of strictly writing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/aws-lambda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 14:06:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://xhocquet.info/reflections/aws-lambda/</guid>
      <description>It feels like every day, it gets harder to put a simple website online. Between defending against spam, vulnerabilities in your dependencies, system maintenance, scaling, and a million others, the sheer amount of knowledge needed can be overwhelming. Even though most sites share the same base, you can be sure you&amp;rsquo;ll spend a significant amount of time patching it together again from past experiences and scattered blog posts.
Services like Heroku, Digital Ocean, and AWS attempt to make all of this more accessible by abstracting it all away in a variety of tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
